

# Matthew Ward

856-473-1845 mattrward1030@gmail .com

Runnemede, NJ 08078

### **SUMMARY**

Proficient Front End Developer effective at developing strong websites that achieve customer objectives. Familiar with working alongside clients to determine needs, create plans and optimize design usability and performance. Well-versed in using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and Javascript and jQuery as well as other resources to accomplish design requirements. Attentive Assistant Store Manager offering over 3 years working in the liquor industry. Focused and enthusiastic demeanor with strong background leading a team. Proven track record for creating positive working and shopping environments.

#### **SKILLS**

- Use Markup Languages
- Style Sheet Languages
- Code Debugging
- CSS
- UI Improvements
- JQuery

- HTML5
- Staff Management
- Inventory Management
- Process Improvement
- Employee Training
- Product Knowledge

# **EXPERIENCE**

Assitant Project Manager

Philadelphia, PA

Self-employeed/Sep 2016 to Dec 2021

- Maintained close connection with project personnel to quickly identify and resolve problems.
- Monitored design processes from conceptual phase through construction.
- Updated project plans based on changing objectives, specifications and staff availability.

#### Driver

Philadelphia, PA

Uber/Jan 2017 to Jun 2021

- Transported clients to specified destinations safely and on-time.
- Achieved consistently high customer scores due to exceptional service.
- Documented daily mileage, gas and other data to log in Excel.
- Utilized GPS to optimize routes and continuously meet estimated delivery times.
- Interacted with customers pleasantly to meet needs and drive satisfaction.

#### Assistant Manager

Voorhees, NJ

Wine Warehouse/Jul 2017 to Mar 2020

- Maintained inventory accuracy by counting stock-on-hand and reconciling discrepancies.
- Planned and prepared workflow schedules, delegating tasks for floor team.
- Assisted Store Manager in evaluating employee performance and cultivating improvement initiatives.
- Directed and led employees, supervising activities to drive productivity and efficiency.
- Supported sales management initiatives to optimize business development.

- Improved efficiency and productivity by implementing organization systems for inventory control.
- Mentored staff to enhance skills and achieve daily targets, using hands-on and motivational leadership.
- Completed inventory audits to identify losses and project demand.
- Delegated daily tasks to team members to optimize group productivity.

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

Some College (No Degree): Physics Rowan University Glassboro, NJ

Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp: Computer Programming University Of Pennsylvania Expected in May 2021 Philadelphia, PA

# WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

• https://mattrward1030.github.io/project-1/